German Painting Photograph Collection
Yale University Arts Library
- M
  - Individual Artists M., 245
    - Marrees, Hans von, 1837-1887., 18 (Box 53)
      Artist's name also spelled "Marees"
    - Mengs, Anton Raphael, 1728-1779., 21 (Box 53)
    - Menzel, Adolf, 1815-1905., 31 (Box 53)
      - Drawings., 8 (Box 53)
      - Paintings., 23 (Box 53)
    - Meyer, George, 1899-., 7 (Box 54)
    - Modersohn-Becker, Paula, 1876-1907., 11 (Box 54)
    - Molzahn, Johannes, 1892-., 6 (Box 54)
    - Mozer, Lucas, active 1431., 17 (Box 54)
    - Muhlich, Hans, 1516-1573., 3 (Box 54)
    - Mueller, Otto, 1874-1930., 5 (Box 54)
    - Multscher, Hans, c.1400-1467., 13 (Box 54)
    - Munter, Gabriele, 1877-1962., 16 (Box 54)
- N-O
  - Miscellaneous Artists N-O., 18 (Box 55)
    - Nagel, Otto, 1894-1967., 2 (Box 55)
    - Nagele, Reinhold, 1884-1972., 1 (Box 55)
    - Nauen, Heinrich, 1880-1940., 1 (Box 55)
    - Nesch, Rolf, 1893-., 1 (Box 55)
    - Neufchatel, (Nicholas) Colin de, 1525-1590., 1 (Box 55)
    - Niederreuther, Thomas, 1909-., 1 (Box 55)
    - Nilson, Johann Esaias, 1721-1788., 1 (Box 55)
    - Notke, Bernt, 1440-1509., 2 (Box 55)
    - Olivier, Ferdinand van, 1785-1841., 3 (Box 55)
    - Olivier, Woldemar, 1791-1859., 1 (Box 55)
    - Oltmanns, Willi, 1905-1979., 1 (Box 55)
    - Ophey, Walter, 1882-1930., 1 (Box 55)
    - Oppenheim, Moritz Daniel, 1800-1882., 1 (Box 55)
    - Ovens, Jurgen, 1623-1678., 1 (Box 55)
  - Individual Artists N-O., 105
    - Nay, Ernst Wilhelm, 1902-1968., 8 (Box 55)
    - Nolde, Emil, 1867-1956., 77 (Box 56)
    - Overbeck, Johann Friedrich, 1789-1869., 10 (Box 56)
- P-Q
  - Miscellaneous Artists P-Q., 22 (Box 57)
    - Palermo, Blinky, 1943-1977., 1 (Box 57)
    - Pankok, Bernhard, 1872-1943., 1 (Box 57)
    - Paudiss, Christopher, 1618-1666., 1 (Box 57)
    - Paulsen, Fritz, 1838-1898., 1 (Box 57)
    - Peiner, Werner, 1897-., 1 (Box 57)
    - Pencz, George, 1500-1550., 2 (Box 57)
    - Peters, Johann Anton de, 1723-1795., 1 (Box 57)
    - Pettenkofen, August von, 1822-1889., 1 (Box 57)
    - Pfeuffer, Helmut, 1933-., 1 (Box 57)
    - Pforr, Franz, 1782-1812., 1 (Box 57)
    - Piene, Otto, 1928-., 1 (Box 57)
    - Pieper, Josef, 1907- .., 1 (Box 57)
    - Piloty, Karl von, 1826-1886., 2 (Box 57)
    - Polke, Sigmar, 1941-., 4 (Box 57)
    - Pollak, T., 1899-., 1 (Box 57)
    - Post, Herman, 1873-1939., 1 (Box 57)
    - Quaglio, Domenico, 1787-1837., 1 (Box 57)
  - Individual Artists P-Q., 61 (Box 57)
    - Pacher, Michael, 1435-1498., 20 (Box 57)
    - Pechstein, Max, 1881-1955., 12 (Box 57)
    - Penck, A. R., 1939-., 6 (Box 57)
    - Pleydenwurff, Hans, active 1457-1472., 7 (Box 57)
    - Pollak, Jan, 1483-1519., 9 (Box 57)
    - Purrmann, Hans, 1880-1966, 7 (Box 57)
- R
  - Miscellaneous Artists R., 39 (Box 58)
    - Rainer, Arnulf, 1929-., 1 (Box 58)
    - Ravenstein, Paul von, 1854-., 1 (Box 58)
    - Rayski, Ferdinand von, 1806-1890., 5 (Box 58)
    - Reichlich, Marx, 1460-1520., 1 (Box 58)
    - Reinhart, Johann Christian, 1761-1847., 3 (Box 58)
    - Rethel, Alfred, 1816-1859., 5 (Box 58)
    - Richter, Gustav, 1823-1884., 3 (Box 58)
    - Ridinger, J. E., (1695-1767)., 1 (Box 58)
    - Riemerschmid, Richard, 1868-1957., 1 (Box 58)
    - Ritschl, Otto, XX Century., 1 (Box 58)
    - Roch, Joseph A., 1768-1839., 2 (Box 58)
    - Rode, H., active 1485-1504., 2 (Box 58)
    - Rohden, Johann Martin van, 1778-1868., 1 (Box 58)
    - Roloff, Otto, 1882-., 1 (Box 58)
    - Romako, Anton, 1832-1889., 1 (Box 58)
    - Roos, J. H., 1631-1685., 2 (Box 58)
    - Rosie, Paul, XX Century., 2 (Box 58)
    - Rothe, G. H., 1935-., 1 (Box 58)
    - Rottenhammer, Hans, 1564-1625., 1 (Box 58)
    - Rummelspacher, Joseph, 1852-1921., 2 (Box 58)
    - Rupprecht, Tini, 1867-1965., 1 (Box 58)
    - Ruthart, C. B. A., 1630-1703., 1 (Box 58)
  - Individual Artists R., 97
    - Ramboux, Johann Anton, 1790-1866., 5 (Box 58)
    - Ratgeb, Jerg, 1480-1526., 8 (Box 58)
    - Richter, Gerhard, 1932-., 9 (Box 58)
    - Richter, Hans, 1888-., 4 (Box 58)
    - Richter, Ludwig, 1803-1884., 17 (Box 58)
    - Ring family, Ludger tom, 1496-1547, Ludger tom, 1522-1584, Herman tom,1521-1597., 6 (Box 59)
    - Rohlfs, Christian, 1849-1938., 24 (Box 59)
    - Rottman, Carl, 1797-1850., 6 (Box 59)
    - Runge, Philipp O., 1777-1810., 28 (Box 59)
- S
  - Miscellaneous Artists S., 64 (Box 60)
    - Salome, 1954-., 1 (Box 60)
    - Sandrant, Joachim von, 1606-1688., 1 (Box 60)
    - Schall, Frederic Jean, 1753-1835., 3 (Box 60)
    - Schick, Gottleib, 1776-1812., 3 (Box 60)
    - Schirmer, Johann, 1807-1863., 1 (Box 60)
    - Schlemmer, Oskar, 1888-1943., 1 (Box 60)
    - Schlichter, Rudolf, 1890-1955., 1 (Box 60)
    - Schluter, Andreas, 1664-1714., 1 (Box 60)
    - Schmidt, Georg Friedrich, 1712-1775., 2 (Box 60)
    - Schmidt, Georg Philipp, 1808-1873., 1 (Box 60)
    - Schmidt, Martin Johann, 1718-1801., 1 (Box 60)
    - Schmurr, Wilhelm, 1878-1959., 1 (Box 60)
    - Schnee, Hermann, 1840-1926., 1 (Box 60)
    - Schoepfer, Abraham (?), active 1527., 1 (Box 60)
    - Scholderer, Otto, 1834-1902., 1 (Box 60)
    - Scholz, Werner, 1898-., 1 (Box 60)
    - Schon, Erhard, 1491-1542., 2 (Box 60)
    - Schonfeld, Johann Heinrich, 1609-1682., 3 (Box 60)
    - Schrader, Julius, 1815-1900., 2 (Box 60)
    - Schrimpf, Georg, 1889-1938., 2 (Box 60)
    - Schrodter, Adolf, 1805-1875., 1 (Box 60)
    - Schuechlin, H., active 1468-1505., 1 (Box 60)
    - Schutz, Christian Georg, 1718-1791., 1 (Box 60)
    - Schwichtenberg, Martel, 1896-1943., 2 (Box 60)
    - Seeger, Hermann, 1857-., 1 (Box 60)
    - Seekatz, Johann Konrad, 1719-1768., 1 (Box 60)
    - Segal, Arthur, 1875-1944., 1 (Box 60, Box 53)
    - Seibold, Christian, 1697/1706-1768., 3 (Box 60)
    - Seiwert, Franz Wilhelm, 1894-1933., 1 (Box 60)
    - Sitte, Willi, 1921- .., 1 (Box 60)
    - Sparmann, Karl Christian, 1805-1864., 1 (Box 60)
    - Springinklee, Hans, c.1495-1523., 1 (Box 60)
    - Steinbruck, Edward, 1803-1882., 1 (Box 60)
    - Steinitz, Kaethe, 1889-1975., 1 (Box 60)
    - Stieler, Joseph, 1781-1858., 1 (Box 60)
    - Stifter, Adelbert, 1805-1868., 1 (Box 60)
    - Stoss, Veit, 1447-1542., 3 (Box 60)
    - Stosskopf, Sebastien, 1597-1657., 1 (Box 60)
    - Strutzel, Otto, 1855-1930., 3 (Box 60)
    - Stuck, Franz von, 1863-1928., 4 (Box 60)
    - Sustris, Friedrich, 1526-1599., 2 (Box 60)
    - Sutter, Joseph, 1781-1866., 1 (Box 60)
    - Swart, Jan, 1469-1535., 2 (Box 60)
  - Individual Artists S., 241
    - Schadow, Johann Gottfried, 1764-1850., 7 (Box 61)
    - Schauffelein, Hans Leonhard, c.1490-c.1539., 8 (Box 61)
    - Schaffner, Martin, active 1508-1536., 9 (Box 61)
    - Schinkel, Karl Friedrich, 1781-1841., 9 (Box 61)
    - Schlemmer, Oskar, 1888-1943., 12 (Box 61)
    - Schmidt-Rottluff, Karl, 1884-1976., 19 (Box 61)
    - Schnorr von Carolsfeld, Julius, 1794-1872., 11 (Box 61)
    - Schongauer, Martin, 1445-1491., 20
      - Drawings., 5 (Box 61)
      - Paintings., 15 (Box 62)
    - Schreyer, Adolphe, 1828-1899., 10 (Box 62)
    - Schumacher, Emil, 1912-., 6 (Box 62)
    - Schwitters, Kurt, 1887-1948., 38 (Box 62)
    - Slevogt, Max, 1868-1932., 6 (Box 62)
    - Soest, Conrad von, active 1405-1422., 8 (Box 62)
    - Soest, Gerard, 1637-1681., 8 (Box 63)
    - Spitweg, Carl, 1808-1885., 34 (Box 63)
    - Stimmer, Tobias, 1539-1584., 9 (Box 63)
    - Strigel, Bernard, 1461-1528., 17 (Box 63)
    - Stuckenberg, Fritz, 1881-1944., 10 (Box 63)
- T
  - Miscellaneous Artists T., 27 (Box 64)
    - Tappert, Georg, 1880-1957., 1 (Box 64)
    - Therbusch, Anna Dorothea, 1722-1782., 1 (Box 64)
    - Thiele, J. A., 1685-1752., 1 (Box 64)
    - Thieler, Fred, 1916-., 1 (Box 64)
    - Thiemann, Carl, 1881-1966., 1 (Box 64)
    - Thuar, Hans, 1887-1945., 2 (Box 64)
    - Tischbein, Johann Friedrich, 1750-1812., 3 (Box 64)
    - Tischbein, Johann H. the Elder, 1722-1789., 1 (Box 64)
    - Tischbein, Johann H. W., 1751-1829., 7 (Box 64)
    - Tischbein, J. Valentin, 1715-1767., 1 (Box 64)
    - Tormer, Benno Friedrich, 1804-1859., 1 (Box 64)
    - Traut, Wolf, active 1510-1520., 1 (Box 64)
    - Trier, Hann, 1915-., 1 (Box 64)
    - Trubner, Wilhelm, 1851-1917., 2 (Box 64)
    - Tubingen, Hans von, c.1400-1462., 2 (Box 64)
    - Tuschen, Julius Bissier, 1893-1965., 1 (Box 64)
  - Individual Artists T., 19 (Box 64)
    - Thoma, Hans, 1839-1924., 19 (Box 64)
- U, V, W, X, Y, Z
  - Miscellaneous Artists U, V, W, X, Y, Z., 40 (Box 65)
    Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings for "U," "V," and "W-Z."
    - Uecker, Gunther, 1930-., 1 (Box 65)
    - Uhde, Fritz von, 1848-1911., 4 (Box 65)
    - Vautier, Benjamin Louis Marc, 1829-1898., 2 (Box 65)
    - Veit, Philipp, 1793-1877., 1 (Box 65)
    - Vischer, Peter the Younger, 1487-1528., 1 (Box 65)
    - Vogeler, Heinrich, 1872-1942., 3 (Box 65)
    - Vordemberge-Gildewart, 1899-., 1 (Box 65)
    - Wagenbauer, Maximilian Joseph, 1774-1829., 1 (Box 65)
    - Wedig, Gotthardt de, 1583-1641., 1 (Box 65)
    - Weiser, Joseph-Emanuel, 1847-1911., 1 (Box 65)
    - Werdehausen, Hans, 1910-., 1 (Box 65)
    - Werner, Carl Friedrich Heinrich, 1808-1894., 1 (Box 65)
    - Weyer, Herman, XVII Century., 1 (Box 65)
    - Wiegman, M., active 1914-1930., 1 (Box 65)
    - Wilck, Johann C., 1774-1819., 1 (Box 65)
    - Willmann, M., 1630-1706., 4 (Box 65)
    - Wissel, Adolf, 1894-1973., 1 (Box 65)
    - Woehnsam, Michael, c.1520., 1 (Box 65)
    - Wyck, Thomas Christian, 1738-1797., 1 (Box 65)
    - Zick, Januarius, 1730-1797., 3 (Box 65)
    - Ziegler, Adolf, 1903-., 1 (Box 65)
    - Ziesenis, Johann, 1716-1777., 2 (Box 65)
    - Zimmermann, Albert, 1808-1888., 1 (Box 65)
    - Zocksberger, Johann, c. 1502., 1 (Box 65)
    - Zugel, Heinrich Johann von, 1850-1941., 4 (Box 65)
  - Individual Artists U, V, W, X, Y, Z., 107
    - Vogel, Hugo, 1855-, 7 (Box 65)
    - Wasmann, Friedrich, 1805-1886., 5 (Box 65)
    - Wertinger, Hans, 1491-1533., 9 (Box 65)
    - Winter, Fritz, 1905-., 7 (Box 65)
    - Winterhalter, Franz Xavier, 1805-1878., 17 (Box 65)
    - Witz, Conrad, 1400-1447., 43 (Box 66)
    - Wolgemut, Michael, 1437-1519., 8 (Box 66)
    - Wols, Alfred Otto Wolfgang Schulz, 1913-1951., 6 (Box 66)
    - Zeitblom, Bartholome, c.1450-1517., 5 (Box 66)